geekzone.co.nz 2016-06-18

# Geekzone Privacy Statement

We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.

  * IP addresses
  * Personal information
  * Cookies
  * Emails
  * Spammers
  * Advertisements
  * External links
  * Third party services
  * Subscriptions
  * Privacy Act 1993
  * Amazon affiliate disclosure
  * MightyApe affiliate disclosure
  * Viglink affiliate disclosure
  * Skimlinks affiliate disclosure
  * PageFair disclosure

 _ **IP addresses**_  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. Your IP address is not used to identify you. However, all posts in our forums and comments to articles have an associated IP address recorded. This IP address is never shown to other users and it is only collected in order to help us to prevent unsolicited posting to our forums (see Spammers below) or other breaches of our Forum Usage Guidelines (FUG).

 _ **Personal information**_  
All users have their user name, country and date of inclusion listed in our User List. This list is only visible to other registered users. The _email_ icon allows users to send private messages between them, but neither the sender's or recipient's email addresses are disclosed. If the user requires privacy, an option is available on your user settings page to hide the user name from this list and prevent other users from contacting via those private messages. 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (such as their email address) and optional personal and demographic information (such as name, city and country).

You public user profile page will be indexed by search engines. If you don't want your name and/or location showing up in search engine results, leave those fields empty. 

_**Cookies**_  
Our site uses cookies to keep track of your login. Cookies are simple data files that store information. We do not install any program on your computer while visiting our site. The information stored in the cookie file is used to store the login information if the user decides to use our auto login feature. We also store a randomly generated value that allows our site to prevent hijacking of forms and controls.

 _ **Emails**_  
We use the user's email address to send forum notifications such as replies to their posts. Users can opt-out of these notifications at any time by clicking a link in those emails. Users can set a profile option to default to subscribe to these forum notifications or not. Users can also opt-in or opt-out of individual discussions when posting a reply. Users can also subscribe to subforums and receive notifications when a new discussion is posted.

Users have access to a page to stop all those forum notifications and can use this at any time.

If the user opts in, we use the contact information (email address) from the registration form to send any important information regarding its registration with Geekzone. 

Our daily email updates are managed by Google Feedburner. We do not supply email address to this service. The user has to actively subscribe to the service directly with Google, through our page.

 _ **Spammers**_  
If spam is found in our forums the associated account is banned and certain information (username, email address and IP address) is submitted to [Stop Forum Spam](http://www.stopforumspam.com/), a third party database service tracking such activities. We do no submit any other information and we do not submit information if a user account is banned for other reasons than spam. We use this service to identify potential spammers and deny registration or access to our forums.

We use the Cloudflare CDN services. Cloudflare may at any time present visitors with a request for information before giving access to our site. This request for information is generally presented when Cloudflare has reasons to believe the visitor is using a compromised browser or system, act as a spammer or a bad actor in general. This request for information is automated and no information is automatically exchanged between us and Cloudflare. We manually add IP address ranges to Cloudflare from time to time to prevent known spammers from accessing our website.

 _ **Advertisement**_  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser server may place or recognize a unique cookie file. We use Google DFP For Small Business to serve ads when you visit our Web site. Ads can be hosted by Google DoubleClick, Tribal Fusion, and other networks. These companies may use information (but not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. 

More specifically Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of DART cookies enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Read [Google's Privacy Terms for more information](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

 _ **External links**_  
This site contains links to other sites. Geekzone is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

_**Third party services**_  
We use scripts from the following services to monitor, manage and monetise our site:

  * Amazon Affiliate
  * Cloudflare
  * DGM Performance
  * Disqus
  * Facebook
  * GeniusLink
  * Google Analytics
  * Google AdSense
  * Google DFP
  * Google Feedburner
  * Google reCaptcha
  * Pagefair
  * PayPal
  * Pingdom
  * PriceMe
  * PushBullet
  * SkimLink
  * Stopforumspam
  * SourcePoint
  * Tradedoubler
  * TribalFusion
  * Twitter
  * Viglink
  * Wootric

 _ **Subscriptions**_  
We use PayPal to manage recurring subscriptions. When a visitor subscribes to our services all personal information as well as credit card information is provided by the user directly to PayPal. We do not receive the credit card information nor store such information in our database.

When using our alternative subscription service webpass.io the transaction is performed directly with the service and we do not receive the credit card information nor store such information in our database.

 _ **Privacy Act 1993**_  
We are also bound by the [New Zealand Privacy Act 1993](http://www.legislation.govt.nz/act/public/1993/0028/latest/DLM296639.html) to make sure your personal information is not disclosed to third parties. More information can be obtained from the [Office of the Privacy Commissioner](https://www.privacy.org.nz/).

 _ **Amazon Affiliate disclosure**_  
Geekzone is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

 _ **MightyApe Affiliate disclosure**_  
Geekzone is a participant in the MightyApe Affiliate Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to mightyape.co.nz.

 _ **Viglink Affiliate disclosure**_  
Geekzone is a participant in the Viglink Affiliate Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising by automatically hyperlinking some keywords to affiliates. You can opt-out of this programme at any time by visiting the [Viglink Opt-Out page](http://www.viglink.com/opt-out).

 _ **Skimlinks Affiliate disclosure**_  
Geekzone is a participant in the Skimlinks Affiliate Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising by automatically hyperlinking some keywords to affiliates. You can opt-out of this programme at any time by visiting the [Skimlinks Opt-Out page](http://optout.skimlinks.com/?tested=1).

 _ **PageFair disclosure**_  
Geekzone is a participant in the PageFair Program, a service that measures the number of adblock users visiting our pages. We also use PageFair to show acceptable ads to those users that block our ads.

 _ **Last update**_ : 6th December 2015
